Hi, I'm Kelli.
I'm an aesthetician and makeup artist at Ultra Salon and Cosmetics and I'm going to give you some tips on how you can fight oily skin.
One of the easiest things that you can do to help with oily skin is actually use a really good hydrator.
Many people with oily skin are really against using a moisturizer and what happens a lot of times is people with oily skin are always using stripping products, trying to strip all the oil out of the skin.
So in turn what happens then is it strips your skin of all its natural oils and tricks your skin into thinking that it's dry.
So in turn, your skin actually produces more oil.
So you can really balance that out just by using a really good hydrator which is an oil-free, water-base moisturizer that's going to balance the oil and water content in the skin and help kind of keep that oily skin in check.
Another thing that you can do is use anything with salicylic acid in it.
Salicylic acid is a really great product for oily skin.
It's a beta-hydroxy acid, helps to pull any impurities out of the pores and helps to control the oil.
You can also use mattifying products.
This is a mattifier.
You can actually take this and pat it.
I will even just take a little bit and pat it here on her nose.
You can even do this over makeup and basically it's just going to help to soak up any shine and keep her really nice and matte all day.
And another thing that you can do is use a really good oil-free foundation and oil-absorbing powders as well.
So those are some things that you can do to help fight oily skin.